Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have another
episode in our series
all about small talk.
That's right, today we're going to take a
look at a work setting where two colleagues
may be run into each other and
they talk very briefly about something.
All right, so let's check out today's
dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Hi Michelle, do you need
to use the photocopier?
Oh hi Jeremy. No, please go ahead.
So how are you Jeremy?
I was talking to Linda
about you only last week.
Oh I'm fine, thanks. I'm
super busy with work actually.
Did you hear about
the Lawson contract?
No, tell me more. Well,
I was discussing the
contract with Bill and
he said that they met the
head of Lawson's last
week. And and hopefully
they're going to confirm
the deal on Wednesday
Fingers crossed. That's
great news Jeremy.
Congratulations. Anyway,
I must get back but
give my regards to your wife Monica.
I will, Michelle. Speak to you soon.
All right, we're back so now let's take a
look at some vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word for you
guys today is photocopier.
Now this is something
that's very common in offices.
That's right, a photocopier also
known as a copy machine or just a copier.
Yeah, this is something
that you use to print on
paper or to copy paper.
So if I have a document,
but I want another
copy of it, I put it on this
machine and it will
copy it and print it out.
That's right. So those are
the ways that you know
this machine by this
name, either photocopier,
copy machine or just
copier. All right, but after
that we have a very
interesting adjective.
This is something that we use
very often in spoken English.
The phrase here, Marco,
was I'm super busy,
but what does it mean to
say you're super something?
That's right. So when
we add the word super
to an adjective, we mean
that we're very, very, very
busy, super busy. All
right, so I'm super hungry.
That means you're
very, very, very hungry.
All right, or I'm super
woman. Also, it means that you
are very much a great
woman. All right, like
Superman is very good at
going fast and doing things.
And so he's super means
great or exceptional.
So in this case, I'm
exceptionally busy.
That's right. And moving
on to the next line where
Jeremy says that he was
discussing the contract with Bill.
So a contract we
know what this means.
Yeah, what is this? So a
contract is a document
and it's something that
you have to have two or
more groups for or
two or more parties.
So Marco, between you and
me, we could have a contract says
that when we come to record,
you will be respectful of me.
That's right. And
then we will both sign.
So it's kind of an agreement
between two, as you
said, or more people and,
but you are promising to
respect the contract and
to do what the contract says.
And if you don't do
what the contract says, we
have a special verb. We
say you broke the contract.
So to break, break a
contract. That's right.
Well, Jeremy was discussing
the contract with Bill,
and they said they met
the head of Lawson's.
Now, Lawson's is a company that
we're just using for the dialogue.
But what does it mean
the head of this company?
Okay, if you think
about the company as a
body, the head is the
top. And in this case, that
would be the president or
the manager or the leader.
It's the most important
person. Okay, so we can
also use this in, in our
offices, for example,
the person in charge of
marketing, the director of
marketing, we also call
him the head of marketing.
Or the head of, yeah,
the head of the sales
division would be the
manager of the sales team or
whoever's most
important in sales.
Another very common
example, I think, is the president,
many times they call
him the head of state.
Yeah, the head of state. So
you can have a dinner with
many heads of state, and those could be
kings or queens or presidents. Very good.
All right, so that's all the vocab
for language. Take away when
we take a short break
and listen to the dialogue
again. Hi, Michelle. Do you
need to use the photocopier?
Oh, hi, Jeremy. No,
please go ahead.
So how are you, Jeremy?
I was talking to Linda
about you only last
week. Oh, I'm fine. Thanks.
I'm super busy
with work, actually.
Did you hear about the loss
in contract? No, tell me more.
Well, I was discussing the contract with
Bill, and he said that they met the head of
loss in last week. And,
and hopefully they're going
to confirm the deal on
Wednesday fingers crossed.
That's great news,
Jeremy. Congratulations.
Anyway, I must get back, but give
my regards to your wife, Monica.
I will, Michelle.
Speak to you soon.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a
look at fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So there's a great phrase here
in fluency builder that we use
when we're trying
to be polite in English.
Michelle says, Oh, hi, Jeremy,
please go ahead. Okay, so
Jeremy asked if she
needs to use the coop, the
photocopier, and he
said, no, Jeremy, it's okay,
go ahead. Please go
ahead. Okay, this literally
means you go, you know,
ahead of me. But in reality,
she's basically saying,
I can wait. You go first.
So if, if you're going into
a building and somebody
opens the door before
you, and they say, please
go ahead, that means
they'll hold the door and
you can go inside first.
So please go ahead.
This is a very polite thing
to do. And if you're in line,
and you see someone is in a
hurry, you can say this to them.
Please go ahead.
All right, very good.
Please go ahead. And
we also going back to the
contract discussed about
confirming the deal. Okay.
All right, so you have a deal
or an agreement or a contract.
But the thing you
do to make sure
that you all agree is you
confirm. So this means you
want to make sure it is
actually going to happen.
And you can actually combine, confirm with
many different things like you can confirm
your tickets to go to
Italy. Or can we confirm
those holidays before I
make my, my bookings?
Because I want to
go to Italy. Exactly.
So you confirm something.
And then Jeremy said a very
strange phrase here, fingers
crossed after talking about the deal.
Okay, so fingers crossed is an interesting
phrase. It doesn't mean, okay, now
go cross your fingers.
But it's something we
save to be superstitious. Because it means
basically, I hope so or hopefully, right?
Because fingers crossed when
you cross your fingers in many
Anglo American kind of
cultures, you are saying
that you hope something will
happen. It's to bring good luck.
All right. So oh
gosh, I really hope
it doesn't rain today. And
then I say fingers crossed.
Yeah, well, fingers
crossed, it doesn't.
And that means that we hope it doesn't.
But now that you said that, maybe it will.
Right. Right. So it's
kind of a superstitious
belief that people have that if you cross
your fingers, it will bring good luck.
Or what you say will happen
will happen or won't happen.
That's right. Fingers
crossed. All right.
So let's take a break now and
listen to our dialogue one last time.
Hi, Michelle. Do you need
to use the photo cab here?
Oh, hi, Jeremy. No,
please go ahead.
So how are you, Jeremy? I was talking
to Linda about you only last week.
Oh, I'm fine. Thanks. I'm
super busy with work, actually.
Did you hear about
the loss in contract?
No, tell me more. Well,
I was discussing the
contract with Bill. And
he said that they met
the head of loss in last
week. And and hopefully
they're going to confirm
the deal on Wednesday
fingers crossed. That's
great news, Jeremy.
Congratulations.
Anyway, I must get back.
But give my regards to your wife, Monica.
I will, Michelle. Speak to you soon.
So this is a very common
scenario in a very,
in an office in a normal
office setting where
maybe you meet your
friend at in the kitchen or
the water cooler, the
photocopier, and you have
very small brief
conversations. That's right.
And you're often
going to hear this called
water cooler talk
because you don't want to
have a long conversation
about something really
deep at the water cooler.
But you do want to talk
about, you know, basic
things, things that you
have in common or work stuff, you know,
how's that paper coming along or how's that?
I heard you had great sales
last week. And so these are
great short things you can
talk about with your colleagues.
Right. Very good.
And as we say, it's
some of the phrases and
the vocab are key things
that you can use to start
up a small conversation,
very brief to talk about, you know, small
things with your colleagues. That's right.
So we hope that you'll tune into
our future lessons about small talk.
And if you have any questions or
comments, you're welcome to find us on
EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.